# **ADRIENNE "LEONA" PONCE**

920 NW 13th Ave. Boynton Beach, FL 33426 • leonaponce@icloud.com • 561.563.1525

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Transitioning from medical organization & coordination roles to business data in order to collaborate with business and IT professionals. Leveraging my affinity for learning, collaborating, and critical thinking to best use tools for business objectives. My background in Cornell sciences and 12 years of combined work in executive assistance, program coordination and medical administration drives me to learn and meet deadlines.

## **EDUCATION**

Cornell University, College of Human Ecology - Ithaca, NY Human Biology, Health, and Society, BSc

May 2015

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Experience with IBM's SPSS statistical software
- Cognitive flexibility (creativity, logical reasoning)
- Clear, concise communication
- Utilization of Office, G Suite & Adobe Suite

- Programming Python & Web Dev
- Simultaneous coordination of projects
- Team Orientedness
- Effective & efficient performance

### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

# Executive Assistant, Practice of Dr. Jerome B. Vincente, MD - Atlantis, FL

June 2007 - August 2019

- Systematized medical records while navigating clinical coding systems (CPT & ICD-10 coding)
- Assisted in the creation of physician clinical notes by recording diagnostic data and chronicling patient care
- Managed calendars, events, and clinic deadlines to ensure smooth practice operations
- Maintained patient confidence and projects operations by keeping HIPAA-protected information confidential

#### Administrative Assistant, Robert Half - West Palm Beach, FL

April 2018 - April 2019

- Adjusted to short-term positions in various office settings throughout the county
- Coordinated with colleagues to address variety of office issues
- Met strict deadlines in a fast-paced, high volume setting

## Program Coordinator II, Harvard Medical School, Boston Children's Hospital

October 2016 - March 2018

- Developed and presented detailed reports laying out data and analysis of ongoing initiatives
- Planned, organized and implemented multiple projects simultaneously to ensure the success of the department
- Proposed and tested new recruiting and attendance initiatives
- Served as administrative assistant to the Director of Program, Dr. Amy Fleischman Director of OWL Childhood Obesity Program
- Augmented knowledge of practices and procedures within the medical field in bariatric populations
- Enrolled families into the program by providing a brief overview and scheduling family medical visits

## Referral Specialist, Private Practice of Dr. Augusto Hoyle, MD - Boynton Beach, FL

June 2015 - August 2015

- Liaised on behalf of patient between medical team and medical insurers
- Orchestrated the timely referral of patients of the private practice to outside facilities and practices
- Oversaw the coordinated transfer of care from primary care physician to specialists and medical facilities
- Collaborated with colleagues to harmonize schedules and capabilities to ensure high quality patient care

#### Treasurer, Cornell University Barbell Club

May 2013 - May 2014

- Established semester budgets for club and provided weekly Treasurer reports for officers
- Arranged logistics, budgets, and documentation to travel to sporting events around the country
- Collected and archived all members' sports waivers and documentation to ensure seamless member participation
- Cataloged and recorded all minutes and dockets for all executive board meetings

# Paid Research Assistant, Cornell University - Department of Nutrition

June 2013 - December 2013

- Researched over 150 childhood obesity interventions in the lab of Dr. David Levitsky, PhD
- Compared and contrasted relative effectiveness of childhood obesity weight loss interventions in scientific trials
- Collaborated on compiling bariatric-related research with fellow undergraduate obesity researchers
- Helped organize and implement study on self-weighing in childhood with fellow researchers

## Research Assistant, Cornell University - Department of Human Development

August 2012 - July 2013

- Utilized IBM SPSS & Matlab to explore the impacts of PTSD and trauma on brain neuroanatomy
- Processed fMRI images to compare and contrast multimodal neuroimages as evidence for stress-related changes to adult brains in those affected by the 9/11 disaster
- Collaborated with Columbia University researchers to collect fMRI data and patient info